All right.
好的。
Let's go on and talk about a bit and much but actually we generally don't use much by itself.
让我们继续讨论一点点，但实际上我们通常不会单独使用太多。
We can say how much but when we're making a statement we always put it with something else like not
我们可以说多少，但是当我们发表声明时，我们总是把它和其他东西放在一起，比如 not
or 2 or so.
或2个左右。
And we'll look at some examples of how we can do that.
我们将看一些我们如何做到这一点的例子。
So a bit now as we did with the last one a little.
所以现在有点，就像我们对最后一个做的那样。
It's often used to make things understated again.
它经常被用来使事情再次被低估。
This one is for uncountable nouns.
这个是不可数名词。
It's why I wrote this here.
这就是我在这里写这篇文章的原因。
So people might use it to say as we did last time I'm a bit tired I'm a bit tired maybe I should I should
所以人们可能会用它来像我们上次那样说我有点累了 我有点累了 也许我应该 我应该
go home.
回家。
But let's look at a couple more examples.
但让我们再看几个例子。
You've got a bit you've got a bit of sauce on your face though you're eating something and nobody wants
虽然你正在吃东西，但没有人想要，你脸上沾了一点酱汁
to have sauce on their face.
在他们的脸上涂上酱汁。
That's not good right.
这不好对。
But you have a little we could say a little you have a little right there.
但是你有一点，我们可以说你有一点。
You didn't notice it and maybe other people saw it but they are too afraid to mention it.
您没有注意到它，也许其他人看到了它，但他们太害怕提及它。
So I'm not afraid to mention it because you probably want someone to mention it so that you can wipe
所以我不害怕提及它，因为您可能希望有人提及它，以便您可以擦拭
it off right.
它关闭的权利。
Wipe it off.
擦掉它。
You've got some sauce on your face here.
你脸上沾了点酱油。
You've got a little sauce on your face here.
你脸上沾了一点酱汁。
OK.
好的。
Very common in this sort of situation.
在这种情况下很常见。
There's a bit of an issue with the server.
服务器有点问题。
So a server is where data is stored and maybe one company has one.
所以服务器是存储数据的地方，也许一家公司有一个。
It's having some problems instead of saying there's a major issue with the server.
它有一些问题，而不是说服务器存在重大问题。 服务器有很大的问题。
Someone who might like to be a little bit understated might say there's a bit of an issue with the server.
可能有点低调的人可能会说服务器有点问题。
Now that can mean because a bit does mean a small amount just like a little does could mean that the
现在这可能意味着因为一点确实意味着少量，就像一点一样可能意味着
issue is very small but it could also mean that the issue is not small.
问题很小，但也可能意味着问题不小。
It could mean that the issue is very big.
这可能意味着问题非常大。
But we're being understated.
但我们被低估了。
We're trying to downplay it a bit and not make it so maybe frantic.
我们试图淡化它，而不是让它变得如此疯狂。
We're not trying to make it sound too too serious.
我们并不想让它听起来太严肃。
There's a bit of an issue with the server.
服务器有点问题。
Now we often use a bit when we want to give feedback to somebody if you tell somebody something about
现在，如果您告诉某人某事，我们想向某人提供反馈时，我们经常使用 bit
themselves that's not good.
自己觉得不好。
That's negative directly and you say you made a mistake.
这直接是负面的，你说你犯了一个错误。
How will they feel.
他们会有什么感觉。
They'll feel bad.
他们会感觉很糟糕。
They won't feel good about that.
他们不会对此感觉良好。
So if we say instead I think I think you're being a bit too critical with the students if I say you're
因此，如果我们改为说，我认为如果我说你是
being too critical with the students critical means that maybe you're criticizing them too much saying
对学生过于挑剔 挑剔意味着你可能批评他们太多了
they're wrong too often.
他们经常犯错。
If we say a bit too critical we really make it softer we really make it sound not friendly it's still
如果我们说的太挑剔了，我们真的让它变得更柔和，我们真的让它听起来不友好它仍然是
direct but it's a lot more polite and it feels like it's a little bit more gentle.
直接但是礼貌多了，感觉也温柔了一点。
And so the person who hears it will probably be more accepting of it.
所以听到它的人可能会更接受它。
So we often use a little and a bit when we're giving feedback.
因此，我们在提供反馈时经常使用一点点。
And I like to call it a softener not the softener that you put in your laundry with your laundry detergent
我喜欢称它为柔软剂，而不是你和洗衣粉一起放入衣物中的柔软剂
but a softener with language to make things sound a little less direct.
而是一种语言的软化剂，使事情听起来不那么直接。
We can use.
我们可以用。
We can use a bit.
我们可以用一点。
We can also use a little.
我们也可以用一点。
OK so let's go on and talk about much.
好的，让我们继续谈论很多。
So is this OK.
这样可以吗。
How much money do you have much.
你有多少钱。
No it's not.
不，这不对。
It's incorrect.
这是不正确的。
Much doesn't go by itself it goes with other words such as not.
很多东西本身并不能与其他词一起使用，例如不。
We can also often say so much too much.
我们也可以经常说太多太多。
And if it's a question how much much more.
如果这是一个问题，还有多少。
OK there's are some ways that we can use much with other words.
好的，有一些方法可以与其他词一起使用。
All right.
好的。
So let's look at some specific specific examples by the way this is uncountable just like the other
所以让我们看一些具体的例子，就像其他的一样不可数
one generally.
一个一般。
OK.
好的。
So how much are these question answer.
那么这些问题的答案是多少。
Not much.
不多。
That's not a good answer because it's not specific because not much for you may be different than not
这不是一个好的答案，因为它不具体，因为对你来说没什么不同可能与没有不同
much for me.
对我来说很重要。
We should give me a number.
我们应该给我一个号码。
But anyway that is grammatically correct.
但无论如何，这在语法上是正确的。
I don't have much money left after my trip.
旅行结束后，我的钱不多了。
Don't have much.
没有太多。
OK do not have much.
OK 没有多少。
This is not.
这不是。
This is the same as not much.
这和不多一样。
It's the same basic grammar.
这是相同的基本语法。
But instead we say do not have much.
但相反，我们说没有太多。
This is a whole piece that we put together which is very common.
这是我们放在一起的一个整体，非常常见。
Too much is also a very common phrase when we are using much so I think this is this whole sentence
当我们使用太多时，太多也是一个非常常见的短语，所以我认为这就是整个句子
is very common.
很常见。
I think I think you've I think you've got way too much time on your hands.
我想我认为你已经我认为你手头的时间太多了。
So somebody is doing something that maybe I feel is a waste of time and you're not being very productive.
所以有人在做一些我觉得是浪费时间的事情，而且你的工作效率不是很高。
And I think you're only doing something because you're lazy and you don't have anything else to do.
而且我认为你只是在做某事，因为你很懒而且你没有其他事情可做。
So I could say I think you've got way too much time on your hands.
所以我可以说我认为你手头的时间太多了。
I mean it's you should be busier.
我的意思是你应该更忙。
So that's usually a criticism.
所以这通常是一种批评。
It's usually a bit critical but this way too much is a very common way to phrase something and time
它通常有点挑剔，但这种方式太多是表达某事和时间的一种非常常见的方式
on your hands way too much time on your hands.
在你的手上太多的时间在你的手上。
This whole piece is a very common expression very common.
这整件作品是一个很普通的表达很普通。
So let's try so much if we can.
因此，如果可以的话，让我们尝试很多。
There's there's so much so much work to do before the party the party on Friday.
在周五的派对之前有很多工作要做。
So many things to do.
有很多事情要做。
Many things to do or so much to do so much to do before the party on Friday.
周五聚会前有很多事情要做或者很多事情要做。
Very common.
很常见。
Pay so much not much and too much are extremely extremely common.
付出这么多不多和太多是极其普遍的。
Just one more example very quickly I've got I've got much more experience than you.
再举一个例子，我很快就得到了，我比你有更多的经验。
I've got much more experience than you.
我的经验比你多。
This one's also quite common.
这个也很常见。
Much more much more.
更多更多。
I have much more.
我还有很多。
OK.
好的。